Wenceslao Ramirez de Villaurrutia Papers, 1862-1924: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Wenceslao Ramirez de Villaurrutia Papers
1862-1924
C0700
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
0.4 linear feet 1 archival box
Ramirez de Villaurrutia, Wenceslao, 1850-1933.
Consists of manuscript notes, reports, and letters of Spanish diplomat Wenceslao Ramirez de Villaurrutia concerning the Spanish position on Morocco and negotiations with statesmen and ambassadors of countries with interest in Morocco.
Wenceslao Ramirez de Villaurrutia was a Spanish diplomat, historian, and politician. Ramirez de Villaurrutia served as Spain's minister of state in 1905 during the reign of Alfonso XIII. As a diplomat, Ramirez de Villaurrutia served as a minister plenipotentiary in Constantinople, Athens, and Brussels and as an ambassador in Vienna, London, Rome, and Paris. In 1918, Ramirez de Villaurrutia received the ns2:title of marqués de Villaurrutia.
The collection consists of manuscript notes and letters of Ramirez de Villaurrutia concerning the Spanish position on Morocco and negotiations with statesmen and ambassadors of countries with interest in Morocco; some correspondence, 1881-1888; and two reports, 1862-1863.
The material is arranged chronologically.
The collection is open for research.
This collection was purchased from Oscar Schreyer in 1991.
Spain. Ministerio de Estado -- History -- Sources.; Diplomats -- Spain -- 20th century.; Morocco -- Foreign relations -- Spain -- 20th century.; Spain -- Foreign relations -- Morocco -- 20th century.; Correspondence -- 19th century.; Reports -- 19th century.; Diplomacy
- "A Eotado" I, 1906-1907; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- "A Eotado" II, 1912; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Correspondence I, 1904-1907; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Correspondence II, 1910-1911; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Correspondence III, 1912; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Correspondence IV, 1919-1924; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1906; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Printed Material, 1912; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Postcards, 1906; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Correspondence of Ramirez De Villaurutia, Wencesslas, Dipolomat, 1862-1888; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- 32101036913968 (Box 1)